<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Covid-19 on Data Science Ideas</title>
    <link>/tags/covid-19/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Covid-19 on Data Science Ideas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 15:15:56 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/covid-19/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking down factors of Covid-19 orientation algorithm by importance</title>
      <link>/post/covid_variable_importance_shapley/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 15:15:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/covid_variable_importance_shapley/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s dig deeper on the important factors of the French Covid-19 patient orientation algorithm! The short answer is fever, diarrhea and number of risk factors, but the real answer is that your target population matters a lot.
Follow me on this journey with 3 variable importance methods and get some insights about how factors interact.
If you are in a hurry, go and see the take-away messages or have a look at the python code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying the French Covid-19 patient orientation algorithm</title>
      <link>/post/covid_scoring_system_presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 08:51:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/covid_scoring_system_presentation/</guid>
      <description>Were you aware that there is an official French decision tree to orient patients towards relevant medical services, depending on their Covid-19 related symptoms? I transformed it into a point-based scoring system (100% logically equivalent), so that a patient can compute his/her score by adding simple weights. Using these Covid-19 orientation algorithms, a more general comparative analysis is carried out concerning decision trees and scoring systems.
If you are in a hurry, go and see the take-away messages!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>