<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fairness on Data Science &amp; AI Ideas</title>
    <link>/tags/fairness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fairness on Data Science &amp; AI Ideas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 12:16:19 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/fairness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring ChatGPT guardails: from protected to forgotten countries (Part 1)</title>
      <link>/post/chatgpt_country_guardrails_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 12:16:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/chatgpt_country_guardrails_study/</guid>
      <description>OpenAI ChatGPT has built guardrails on limiting the generation of negative content. How do these guardrails behave for countries? Spoiler: there are some gaps and disparities in ChatGPT safety mechanisms. Based on 24100 ChatGPT queries, this blog post is an exploration of ChatGPT responses when prompted to generate negative content about a country.
If you are in a hurry, go and see the early results.
1. Context: ChatGPT guardrails and harmful content prevention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death sentences and race-ethnicity</title>
      <link>/post/fairness_justice_death_sentence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 10:00:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fairness_justice_death_sentence/</guid>
      <description>This post will present and explain a situation where Black Lives Mattered less. In Oklahoma, from 1990 to 2012, 143 offenders were sentenced to death. In 2017, Pierce et al.1 collected and analyzed the homicide data (4668 offenders) and the death sentences. It shows that there are several race/ethnicity effects involved in the death sentences outcomes. The paper contains all details. Terminology used (&amp;ldquo;nonwhite&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;race&amp;rdquo;) comes from the paper. I don&amp;rsquo;t like the &amp;ldquo;nonwhite&amp;rdquo; term, but I cannot easily replace it each time with Black, Hispanic, Native American and Asian.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>