<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>XAI on Trusted AI Ideas</title>
    <link>/tags/xai/</link>
    <description>Recent content in XAI on Trusted AI Ideas</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 15:36:11 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/xai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do you know the 4 types of additive Variable Importances?</title>
      <link>/post/variable_importance_feature_attribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 15:36:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/variable_importance_feature_attribution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Facing complex models, both computer simulation and machine learning practitioners have pursued similar objectives: to see how results could be broken down and linked to the inputs.&#xA;Whether it is called &lt;strong&gt;Sensitivity Analysis&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Variable Importance&lt;/strong&gt; in the context of explainable AI, some of their methods share an important component: the &lt;strong&gt;Shapley values&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article presents a structured 2 by 2 matrix to think about Variable Importances in terms of their goals.&#xA;Focused on additive feature attribution methods, the 4 identified quadrants are presented along with their &amp;ldquo;optimal&amp;rdquo; method: SHAP, SHAPLEY EFFECTS, SHAPloss and the very recent SAGE.&#xA;Then, we will look into Shapley values and their properties, which make the 4 methods theoretically optimal.&#xA;Finally, I will share my thoughts on the perspectives concerning Variable Importance methods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking down factors of Covid-19 orientation algorithm by importance</title>
      <link>/post/covid_variable_importances_shapley/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 15:15:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/covid_variable_importances_shapley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s &lt;img style=&#34;float: left;&#34; src=&#34;/img/post/covid_variable_importances_shapley/large_piechart.png&#34; width=&#34;120&#34;&gt; dig deeper on the &lt;strong&gt;important factors&lt;/strong&gt; of the French Covid-19 patient orientation algorithm!&#xA;The short answer is &lt;strong&gt;fever&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;diarrhea&lt;/strong&gt; and number of &lt;strong&gt;risk factors&lt;/strong&gt;, but the real answer is that your target population matters a lot.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Follow me on this journey with &lt;strong&gt;3 variable importance methods&lt;/strong&gt; and get some insights about how factors interact.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are in a hurry, &lt;a href=&#34;#take_away_message&#34;&gt;go and see the take-away messages&lt;/a&gt; or have a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/datajms/COVID19_attribution&#34;&gt;python code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying the French Covid-19 patient orientation algorithm</title>
      <link>/post/covid_scoring_system_presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 08:51:53 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/covid_scoring_system_presentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Were you aware that there is an &lt;strong&gt;official French decision tree&lt;/strong&gt; to orient patients towards relevant medical services, depending on their Covid-19 related symptoms?&#xA;I transformed it into a &lt;a href=&#34;/post/covid_scoring_system_presentation/#01_orientation_score&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;point-based scoring system&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (100% logically equivalent), so that a patient can compute his/her score by adding simple weights.&#xA;Using these Covid-19 orientation algorithms, a more general &lt;strong&gt;comparative analysis&lt;/strong&gt; is carried out concerning decision trees and scoring systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are in a hurry, &lt;a href=&#34;#take_away_message&#34;&gt;go and see the take-away messages&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
